MARIO VIENS

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

in /in/marioviens (7) tendermario

SUMMARY

I am a software developer creating web experiences with current technologies. I enjoy wearing many hats as a full stack developer that keeps an eye on dev ops, has a focus in back-end, but also experienced with React. As a student and a teacher, I love to share knowledge and better those around me.

I started out in pure mathematics and now enjoy working on innovation and ground-breaking technology, with experience in virtual reality, analytics, and the non-profit sector.

I enjoy learning new languages, take on new challenges, and invite others to challenge themselves. I enjoy iteration with a focus on structure, collaboration, and uniform code practices.

EDUCATION

2016 Lighthouse Labs

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp

2012 Thompson Rivers University

Mathematics

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript, PostgreSQL, MYSQL, HTML5, CSS3, MongoDB, Ruby, Python, Pug/Jade, TypeScript

LIBRARIES, FRAMEWORKS,

AND SYSTEMS

Rails, Django, React, Redux, Express, Node.js, jQuery, APIs, Webpack, CI, AWS, Heroku

CUSTOMER SUPPORT

Technical Support, Knowledge Base Creation, Project Management, Customer Support, Zendesk,

Order Management, Documentation and Training

EDUCATION

Tutoring, Training, Documentation Creation, Mentoring, Project Evaluation

ACTIVITIES

June 2017 to Current

Lighthouse Labs Alumni Food & Code · Coordinator

A meet up for people that want to get together and code. No talks. No non-coders that are trying to network.

PROJECTS

Heavy Visualizer

Web-based 3D customizable music visualizer. Can upload or drag and drop a song into the window, or enable mic. Created as a 2-person team in two weeks.

Used Javascript, ThreeJS, jQuery, Web Audio API

Nanoleaf Lightpanel CLI

A little test project to program Nanoleaf Light Panels by hitting the hardware's API. Is a fork of a fork of an unofficial python wrapper of the official API.

ordr

Online customer food ordering and restaurant order manager as a part of a 3-person team within 5 days. Automated restaurant calling and automated customer texting for immediate updates.

Used JavaScript, Express, EJS, Node.js, Postgres database hosted on Heroku, incorporated Twilio API

Make Food

A passion project web app with Nima Boscarino where you enter the amount of money you want to spend and it sends you food. Uses puppeteer.

MARIO VIENS

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

EMPLOYMENT

Feb. 2019 to Current Lighthouse Labs

Project Evaluator Lead · Vancouver, BC

Evaluating the project evaluators for consistent quality feedback for students.

Aug. 2018 to Current Mentor

 $\label{thm:model} \mbox{Mentoring students, code review, help diagnose bugs and point them in the right direction. Ad hoc}$

mini lectures on various programming concepts.

Curriculum includes: Javascript, Node, Express, React, Redux, jQuery, Ruby, Rails, Mongodb, Postgres

Oct. 2017 to Mar. 2019 Project Evaluator

Evaluating the projects students submit with feedback on organization, version control, code style,

best practices, and solutions.

July 2017 to Apr. 2019 uForis VR

Web Developer · Vancouver, BC

Main web developer developing the web-side of a VR company including the internal panorama image processing software, and prototyping their 3D panorama web viewer. Reworked the frontend

to use Material.UI design language and TypeScript. Created documentation for the web app

codebase. Feature development, and database management.

Set up the continuous integration architecture with BitBucket, Git, AWS, and PM2.

Worked with React, Redux, Node.js, Koa, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, and Three.JS.

Mar. 2017 to June 2017 Watercooler Analytics

Web Developer · Vancouver, BC

Web developer for an analytics software company for convention centres and destination market organizations. Revamped their main website during this time and worked on iterating over custom

software builds.

Stack in React, React Datagrid, Mongodb, and Ruby on Rails.

Jan. 2017 to Mar. 2017 Vancouver Community Network

Full-Stack Web Developer · Vancouver, BC

Sole developer on the Binners' Project app - building an app for users to connect with binners/waste

pickers.

Stack built in Node.JS, Javascript, Express, Jade/Pug, Bootstrap.

Feb. 2014 to Sept. 2016 Convergys

Technical Support Professional III · Chilliwack, BC

VR Technical Support, Project Management, Documentation and Training.

A core member of the global escalations team for hardware and software technical support for a

consumer virtual reality headset company.

Apr. 2012 to July 2012 Thompson Rivers University

Mathematics Researcher · Kamloops, BC

A part of a research team working on the Graceful Tree Conjecture in Graph Theory.

Dec. 2009 to Sept. 2016 Mathematics and Sciences Tutor · Kamloops, Vancouver

University and high school sciences and mathematics tutor.